Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. It's time to talk about some
macroeconomic principles, meaning we're
going to switch over to my lovely
economics background. Man, this
background brings back so many memories
of when I actually tried to review AP
economics on this channel. Got to say,
glad I didn't finish those courses.
Anyway, let's talk about what the term
LZ fair means. When I plug it into
Google Translate, it literally means in
French, let it happen. And this actually
perfectly explains the concept. If you
are adopting a LZ fair mentality, it
means you are taking a hands-off
approach. You don't intervene at all and
let all problems get solved without any
intervention. Moving back over to our
history background, there were
increasing debates over whether the
government should be involved in
regulating businesses and had a hand in
their own economics. And I'm sure you
can guess the result. The US will choose
to adopt a lzair mentality. However, you
do see attempts to intervene like the
Interstate Commerce Act and the Sherman
Antitrust Act, but those governmental
actions will be poorly enforced. In
fact, a good example to counter these
points is President Grover Cleveland's
veto to sending relief to farmers. This
shows the US actively refusing to help
their own economy in hardship. But
here's your contradiction. Because while
the US government didn't intervene at
home, they definitely intervened around
the world. The point is the US wants
more markets and more resources. Your
two examples to memorize here is the US
attaining the lovely Hawaii and Alaska.
Hawaii was attained for access to the
sugar industry and Alaska was attained
for its positioning and resources. There
are also other examples, but you don't
necessarily need to know them all. On
the screen now are AP style questions
for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.